Fei Pan

Research Fellow of CSE, University of Michigan

G google-scholar $\mbox{\ensuremath{\mbox{$\widehat{}}}}$ feipan.info $\mbox{\ensuremath{\mbox{$\square$}}}$ feipan@umich.edu $\mbox{\ensuremath{\mbox{$\square$}}}$ +1-734-546-5633

Research Interest: My passion is to create a general AI system for computer vision tasks that is to proof to be robust, versatile, and unified among all the tasks. My current research focuses on high-level computer vision models such as detection and segmentation and their adaptability and generalization to novel domains. Besides, I am also interested in generative models including diffusion models and large-scale vision and language models.

EDUCATION

KAISTMar 2018 - Aug 2023

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering | Advisor: In So Kweon

Thesis: Geometric-guided Domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation

KAIST Mar 2016 - Feb 2018

 ${\it M.S.}$ in Electrical Engineering | Advisor: Chang D. Yoo

Thesis: Deep Recursive Segmentation Networks

Xidian University Aug 2011 - Jul 2015

B.S. in Telecommunications Engineering | Class Rank: 1/41

GPA: 3.7/4.0

EXPERIENCE

University of Michigan Sep 2023 - Current

Research Fellow | Advisor: Stella X. Yu

Bosch Robert GmbH May 2021 - Nov 2021

Research Internship | Advisor: Yu Gao

Visbody Co., Ltd

Aug 2015 - Feb 2016

Internship | Advisor: Shaoyi Yang

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Proceedings

[1] ImageNet-D: Benchmarking Neural Network Robustness on Diffusion Synthetic Object.

Chengshuang Zhang, Fei Pan, Junmo Kim, In So Kweon, Chengzhi Mao.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024

Highlight Poster (Acceptance Rate < 2.6%)

Paper | Code

[2] MoDA: Leveraging Motion Priors from Videos for Advancing Unsupervised Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmentation.

Fei Pan, Xu Yin, Seokju Lee, Axi Niu, Sungeui Yoon, In So Kweon.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshop, 2024

Best Paper Award

Paper

[3] Masking-augmented Collaborative Domain Congregation for Multi-target Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmentation.

Fei Pan*, Dong He*, Xu Yin, Chenshuang Zhang, Munchurl Kim.

IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV), 2024

[4] Zero-shot Building Attribute Extraction from Large-Scale Vision and Language Models.

Fei Pan, Sangryul Jeon, Brian Wang, Frank Mckenna, Stella Yu.

IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2024

Paper | Code | Poster

[5] ML-BPM: Multi-teacher Learning with Bidirectional Photometric Mixing for Open Compound Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmentation.

Fei Pan, Sungsu Heo, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon.

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.

Paper | Poster

[6] Attentive and Contrastive Learning for Joint Depth and Motion Field Estimation.

Seokju Lee, Francois Rameau, Fei Pan, In So Kweon.

IEEE / CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021

Paper | Code

[7] Two-phase Pseudo Label Densification for Self-training based Domain Adaptation.

Inkyu Shin, Sanghyun Woo, Fei Pan, In So Kweon.

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020.

Paper

[8] Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision.

Fei Pan, Inkyu Shin, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon.

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020.

Oral Presentation (Acceptance Rate < 0.7%)

Paper | Code | Project Page

[9] Variational Prototyping-Encoder: One-Shot Learning with Prototypical Images.

Junsik Kim, Tae-Hyun Oh, Seokju Lee, Fei Pan, In So Kweon.

 $\it IEEE\ /\ CVF\ Conference\ on\ Computer\ Vision\ and\ Pattern\ Recognition\ (CVPR),\ 2019.$

Paper | Code

[10] Driver Drowsiness Detection System Based on Feature Representation Learning Using Various Deep Networks. Sanghyuk Park, Fei Pan, Sunghun Kang, and Chang D. Yoo.

Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) Workshop on Driver Drowsiness Detection from Video, 2016. Paper

JOURNAL ARTICLES

[1] CCTV-Calib: a Toolbox to Calibrate Surveillance Cameras Around the Globe.

Francois Rameau, Jaesung Choe, Fei Pan, Seokju Lee, and In So Kweon.

Machine Vision and Applications, 2024

Paper | Code

PREPRINT & WORKING PAPERS

[1] OpenSlot: Real-World Open Set Recognition with Object Centric Learning. Xu Yin, Fei Pan, Yuchi Huo, Zixuan Xie, Sungeui Yoon.

Under Review

[2] Fine-grained Background Representation for Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation.

Xu Yin, Woobin Im, Dongbo Min, Yuchi Huo, Fei Pan, Sungeui Yoon.

Under Review

[3] Labeling Where Adapting Fails: Cross-Domain Semantic Segmentation with Point Supervision via Active Selection.

Fei Pan, Framcois Rameau, Junsik Kim, In So Kweon.

arXiv:2206.00181, 2022

PROJECTS

NATURAL HAZARD ENGINEERING

AI/ML for Structure Feature Inference | Research & Software Dev.

 $Sept\ 2023\ -\ Current$

Funded by: National Science Foundation, United States

Goal: Development of AL/ML tools to infer the features of buildings and terrains.

My Work: Experiment with large language models to infer building features, with a proof-of-concept study on classification and segmentation.

INTELLIGENT TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS

Robust Vehicle Detection from Multi-camera Views | Research Internship

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Funded by: Robert Bosch GmbH

Goal: New algorithms for domain adaptation in various utilization environments with fusion of multiple visual data. My Work: Developing a new framework of domain adaptation for multiple perception tasks in driving scenes, with a specific focus on vehicle detection from multiple views from CCTV cameras in road scenes, considering the domain gaps among multiple cameras and diverse weather conditions

Shared Sensing for Cooperative Cars | Project Member

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Funded by: Robert Bosch GmbH

Goal: Developing new technologies toward the collaboration between a swarm of vehicles and CCTV cameras.

My Work: Conducting static background using background subtraction algorithms; to build a CNN-based segmentation model for road mark detection.

Autonomous Driving

Driver Assistant Active Safety | Project Member

Apr 2016 - Feb 2017

Funded by: National Core Research Center of South Korea

Goal: Build a learning-based high-performance vision algorithm for active safety driver assistance.

My Work: Participating in creating drowsiness labeling dataset, and building a CNN-based algorithm for detecting the drowsiness status of the drivers.

Scholarship & Awards

Robert Bosch Ph.D. Scholarship Sept 2019 - Aug 2021

Robert Bosch GmbH | Funding Awarded: ${\in}44{,}000~\mathrm{EUR}~(\sim47,100~\mathrm{USD})$

Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Dec 2020

Goodix Technology Scholarship Sept 2015

Goodix Technology Co., Ltd | Funding Awarded: \$5,000 RMB (~ 700 USD)

Outstanding Student Jul 2015

Xidian University

Academic Reviews

Conference Review

IEEE / CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023, 2024

IEEE / CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023

IEEE / CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2022

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning Theory and Practice, 2021

The International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning for Reasoning and Perception, 2021

JOURNAL REVIEW

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2023

Image and Vision Computing, 2023

Neurocomputing, 2023

Computer Vision and Image Understanding, 2023

Pattern Recognition Letters, 2022

Neurocomputing, 2022

Academic Services

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Advanced Topics in Deep Learning for Robotics and Vision: Domain Adaptation

Teaching Assistant, 2021

Deep Learning for Computer Vision: Generative Adversarial Learning

Teaching Assistant, 2020

Talks & Keynote Speakings

Enhancing Robustness in Deep Learning: Insights from Unsupervised Domain Adaptation, Compound Domain Challenges, and Large Language Models.

2024 Machine Learning Conference, Eastern Michigan University, April 13 2024

Zero-shot Building Attribute Extraction from Large-Scale Vision and Language Models.

NHERI Computational Symposium, UCLA Luskin Conference Center, Feb 1 2024

Unsupervised Intra-domain Adaptation for Semantic Segmentation through Self-Supervision.

Oral Presentation at CVPR, Jun 16 2020 (Remote)

Driver Drowsiness Detection System Based on Feature Representation Learning Using Various Deep Networks. The ACCV Workshop on Driver Drowsiness Detection from Video, Taipei, Nov 24 2016

STUDENT MENTORING

Brian Wang, Master Student at CSE, University of Michigan